American Association for Social Security Records 5002
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Social Security - Reduction of Tax (Unemployment Insurance), 1940 (Box 30, Folder 36)
- Social Security - Reaction of Individuals and Organizations, 1936-1940 (Box 30, Folder 35)
  Clippings, pamphlets, announcement
- Social Security - Progress Reports, 1935-1942 (Box 30, Folder 34)
  Address, releases, clippings, summary of progress
- Social Security - Post War Problems, 1941-1942 (Box 30, Folder 33)
  Clippings, pamphlets, articles
- Social Security - Internal Revenue Bureau -Collection of Taxes, 1940 (Box 30, Folder 19)
- Social Security - Perkins, Frances (National Conference on Social Insurance), 1933-1934 (Box 30, Folder 31)
  lists of names re Advisory Council
- Social Security - Reserve Account and Use of Reserves (Attacks, etc.), 1937-1942 (Box 30, Folder 40)
  Release, clippings, form letter
- Social Security - Old Age Pensions, 1940-1941 (Box 30, Folder 29)
- Social Security - Old Age Insurance, 1936-1939 (Box 30, Folder 28)
- Social Security - Officials, Statements, Biographies, 1938-1941 (Box 30, Folder 27)
  Clippings, releases, articles, speech
- Social Security - Negroes, 1941 (Box 30, Folder 26)
  Clippings, release
- Social Security - Mothers' Pensions, 1931 (Box 30, Folder 25)
  Clippings, articles, bibliography, notes, reports, publication
- Social Security - Migratory Workers, 1940-1941 (Box 30, Folder 24)
- Social Security - Miles, Vincent M., 1936-1937 (Box 30, Folder 23)
  Clippings, addresses
- Social Security - Merrill Murray, 1939 (Box 30, Folder 22)
- Social Security - Perkins, Frances, 1935-1943 (Box 30, Folder 32)
  Clippings, address by Perkings, "The Beveridge Plan"
- Social Security - State Officials, 1936-1938 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  Release, clippings
- Social Security - Roosevelt on Social Security, 1939-1940 (Box 31, Folder 1a)
- Social Security - Winant, John C., 1936-1940 (Box 31, Folder 15)
- Social Security - Wage Records, 1935-1942 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  Releases, clippings
- Social Security - Vandenberg, Sen., 1937 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  Clippings, "Discussion of Social Security Act," by Arthur H. Vandenberg
- Social Security - Unemployment Insurance Operations, 1937-1938 (Box 31, Folder 12)
- Social Security - Unemployment Insurance - Legislation, Operation, Statements, 1936-1938 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  Releases, clippings, articles
- Social Security - Women Workers, 1940-1941 (Box 31, Folder 17)
- Social Security - State Officials, 1936-1938 (Box 31, Folder 9)
- Social Security - Woodward, Ellen S., 1938-1940 (Box 31, Folder 18)
- Social Security - Stamp System, 1940-1941 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  Release, pamphlets, article, notes
- Social Security - Soldiers' Dependents' Allowances, 1942-1943 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  Clippings, drafts of proposals, leg. bills, "The Cost and Administration of Family Allowances," by Harry Grossman
- Social Security - Soldiers Benefit Rights, Etc., 1942-1944 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  Articles, clippings, legislative bills
- Social Security - Social Security Taxes, 1943-1944 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  Clippings, notes, statement by A. Altmeyer
- Social Security - Seidmann, H.P., 1936-1937 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  Clippings, releases, article
- Social Security - Seasonal Workers, 1940-1941 (Box 31, Folder 2)
- Social Security - Rosenberg, Mrs. A.M., 1936-1942 (Box 31, Folder 1)
- Social Security - Tabular Analysis of Law, 1936-1938 (Box 31, Folder 10)
- Family Allowances, 1933-1941 (Box 31, Folder 26)
  Clippings, legislative bills, release, notes
- Professions - Condition of, 1931-1935 (Box 31, Folder 34)
- Pension Plans, 1930-1931 (Box 31, Folder 33)
  Clippings, articles, pamphlets, releases, mss. re GE unemployment plan, 11 p.
- Pensions and Politics, 1938-1940 (Box 31, Folder 32)
- Pensions for the Blind, 1932-1937 (Box 31, Folder 31)
  Articles, clippings, legislative bills, notes, statistical information
- International Labor Organization, 1934-1935 (Box 31, Folder 30)
  Clippings, releases, articles, issues of Monthly Summary of the ILO
- Home Work, 1936-1937 (Box 31, Folder 29)
- Social Security - Witte, E.E., 1935-1937 (Box 31, Folder 16)
- Federal Aid to the States and General Expenditures, 1933-1940 (Box 31, Folder 27)
  Pamphlets, release, clippings
- Savings, 1941-1942 (Box 31, Folder 35)
  Issues of The Month's Work published by the National Assn. of Mutual Savings Banks
- Employment Agencies, 1930-1936 (Box 31, Folder 25)
  Releases, articles, clippings, notes, pamphlets
- Domestic Labor Clippings, 1940-1941 (Box 31, Folder 24)
- Dependent's Allowances, 1941-1942 (Box 31, Folder 23)
  Articles, legislative bills, clippings, notes
- Blind and Dependent Laws CCH Sheets - Oregon - Wyoming, 1937-1939 (Box 31, Folder 22)
- Blind and Dependent Laws CCH Sheets - Massachusetts - Oregon, 1937-1939 (Box 31, Folder 21)
- Blind and Dependent Lavs CCH sheets by State - Alabama - Massachusetts, 1937-1939 (Box 31, Folder 20)
- Social Security - Workers Education Bureau - Plans, 1936 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  Booklets re this topic
- Governor's Messages, 1944 (Box 31, Folder 28)
  Printed messages from various states re social security programs
- Unemployment - Michigan, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  Pamphlet
- Unemployemnt - Benefits - Trade Union Plans, 1928-1931 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  Articles, printed materials, and a booklet re labors' benefit plans; unions include the Brhd. of Railway Clerks, Amalgamated Workers of America, and others
- Unemployment - Bibliography, 1930-1932 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  Includes a list of social science abstracts, readers' guide references and some clippings on unemployment
- Unemployment - Causes - Purchasing Power, 1930-1931 (Box 32, Folder 4)
- Unemployment - Causes - Technological Development, 1927-1932 (Box 32, Folder 5)
- Unemployment - Connecticut Valley, 1932 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  Reports
- Unemployment - Consequences, 1930 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  Articles, pamphlets, clippings, notes
- Unemployment - Consequences, 1931-1934 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  Clippings, articles, printed mss. re the effects of the depression
- Unemployment - Consequences, 1930-1936 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  Clippings, articles, releases
- Unemployment - Extent - 1930 and Before, 1927-1930 (Box 32, Folder 10)
- Unemployment - Extent - 1930 to 1933, 1931-1933 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  Articles, clippings, reports
- Unemployment - Extent, 1931-1939 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  Clippings, releases, articles
- Unemployment - Benefits - Company Plans, 1929-1936 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  Clippings and articles describing company benefit plans
- Unemployment - Massachusetts, 1931-1932 (Box 32, Folder 14)
- Unemployment Remedies - Share Work, 1932-1938 (Box 32, Folder 29)
  Clippings, pamphlets, address by W. Teagle, statement
- Unemployment - -New Jersey, 1939 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  Explanation of the unemployment insurance compensation lav of New Jersey
- Unemployment - Nevada, 1931-1932 (Box 32, Folder 17)
- Unemployment - New York State, 1930-1932 (Box 32, Folder 18)
- Unemployment - New York State, 1933-1937 (Box 32, Folder 19)
- Unemployment - Ohio, 1928-1934 (Box 32, Folder 20)
  Pamphlets, reports, article
- Unemployment - Oregon, 1915 (Box 32, Folder 21)
  Report
- Unemployment - Pennsylvania, 1931-1938 (Box 32, Folder 22-23)
- Unemployment Remedies - General, 1928-1930 (Box 32, Folder 24)
  Legislative bill, clippings, articles, publications
- Unemployment Remedies - Loans to Workers, 1927 (Box 32, Folder 25)
  Articles, publication
- Unemployment Remedies - Relief, 1931-1932 (Box 32, Folder 26)
- Unemployment Remedies - Repeal of l8th Amendment, 1932-1934 (Box 32, Folder 27)
  Pamphlets, clippings re prohibition
- Unemployment Remedies - Rural Rehabilitation, 1934-1935 (Box 32, Folder 28)
- Unemployment - General, 1928-1938 (Box 32, Folder 13)
- Unemployment Compensation - Merit Rating -Clippings and Releases, 1939 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  Newspaper clippings, a reading list, and a report by the Bureau of Research and Statistics
- Unemployment Remedies - Stabilization General, 1928-1937 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  Newspaper articles and printed materials on the problem of unemployment, suggesting programs for stabilization of jobs, and pointing out the necessity of this
- Unemployment Remedies - Stabilization by Industries and Companies, 1929-1938 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  Newspaper articles and printed materials reporting methods and plans used by various industries during the depression to alleviate cyclical and seasonal unemployment in attempts to create a stabilization of jobs and wages; companies reported on include Proctor and Gamble, GE, etc. also newspaper clipping on social security and its relation to unemployment benefits
- Unemployment - Rhode Island, 1937 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  Description of Rhode Island's unemployment compensation law
- Unemployment - Statistical Studies - States and Cities, 1930-1937 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  Report on the problems of international employment statistics, and unemployment surveys; and articles on unemployment census-taking
- Unemployment - Study Outlines, 1929-1935 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  Reports and pamphlets on unemployment - its causes and some possible ones; sources include the National Board of the YWCA, and Pennsylvania's State Emergency Relief Administration, etc
- Unemployment - Tragedies - Pictures - Sketches, 1933-1937 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  Newspaper photographs and articles portraying the depressed state of the union - bread lines, child labor, etc.
- Unemployment - Washington (State), 1930-1931 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  An employment survey in the Pacific Northwest -winter of 1930-31
- Unemployment - Compensation - Merit Rating, 1941-1942 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  Explains the merit rating system in unemployment -the basic issues involved and its objectives, includes booklets and other printed materials
- Unemployment Compensation - Merit Rating -General, 1940-1944 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  Printed materials and pamphlets from the Joint Conference against Merit-rating; A. J. Altmeyer, "Undermining Unemployment Insurance,"
- Unemployment Remedies - Shorter Hours or Week, 1931-1933 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  The six hour work day and five day work week are discussed in newspaper articles from the NY Times, Federation News, etc.; also, printed material on these topics
- Unemployment Compensation - Merit Rating Clippings and Releases, 1933-1938 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  Pros and Cons of merit-rating explained in clippings and releases
- Unemployment Insurance - America - Advocates, 1930-1934 (Box 33, Folder 24)
  Various proposals for unemployment insurance are explained in articles and printed materials by Senator Wagner, William Leiserson, Harry Laidler, etc.
- Unemployment Compensation - Merit Rating -Clippings and Releases, 1940 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  Reports, articles, clippings, and printed materials re merit rating; a statement of Mr. Epstein before the Committee on Employers Experience Rating; an annotated bibliography on experience (merit) rating; a report on merit-rating from the Committee on Social Legislation, National Lawyers Guild; proceedings of the 7th National Conference on Labor Legislation, etc.
- Unemployment Compensation - Merit Rating -Clippings and Releases - Massachusetts, 1939-1941 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  Clippings, reports to Gov. Saltonstall
- Unemployment Compensation - Merit Rating -Clippings and Releases - New York, 1940 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  Printed materials and reports re a proposed merit-rating amendment to the unemployment insurance law of NY, and Gov. Lehman's veto of it
- Unemployment Compensation - Merit Rating -Clippings - New York, 1939-1940 (Box 33, Folder 17)
  Clippings re merit rating
- Unemployment Compensation - Merit Rating -Clippings and Releases - Pennsylvania, 1940 (Box 33, Folder 18)
  Clippings, pamphlets and reports on merit-rating; "Is Experience (Merit) Rating Practical in Unemployment Compensation in Pennsylvania," by Pa. Assn. for Sound Social Security, etc.
- Unemployment Compensation - Merit Rating -Clippings and Releases - Other States, 1940-1941 (Box 33, Folder 19)
  Articles and clippings from various states, i.e. Alaska, Colorado, New Jersey, etc.
- Unemployment Compensation - Philosophy - Articles, 1941-1943 (Box 33, Folder 20)
- Unemployment Insurance - Abroad - General, 1930-1937 (Box 33, Folder 21)
  Articles, printed materials and reports covering unemployment insurance abroad; also included Is a report from the ILO Conference held in Geneva
- Unemployment Insurance - Advocation and Endorsement by Individuals and Organizations, 1930-1934 (Box 33, Folder 22)
  Articles and printed materials expressing views on unemployment insurance - sources include the YWCA, William Leiserson, Paul Douglas, etc.
- Unemployment Insurance - America - General, 1930-1937 (Box 33, Folder 23)
  Newspaper and magazine articles, printed materials, on U. S. programs; included are statements from the Consumers League of New York; a Debate Handbook from the Univ. of Pittsburgh; various opinions and explanations of the subject
- Unemployment Compensation - Merit Rating -Clippings and Releases, 1941-1942 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  General Clippings and printed materials re merit-rating; "The Demerits in Merit Rating" by Epstein
- Unemployment Insurance - Hawaii, 1937-1944 (Box 34, Folder 14a)
  Pamphlets, newsletters
- Unemployment Insurance - Byrne-Killgrew Bill, 1935 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  Telegrams sent to Sen. Byrne; a summary of the revised Byrne-Killgrew Bill; information re the unemployment insurance hearing
- Unemployment Insurance - Census, 1941-1943 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  Graphs, tables, publications of the Federal Security Agency - Social Security Board
- Unemployment Insurance - Census, 1941 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  Publications, reports, statistical charts
- Unemployment Insurance - Census, 1940 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  Publications, statistics
- Unemployment Insurance - Census, 1939 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  A-N completed survey forms by states
- Unemployment Insurance - Census, 1939 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  Census N-W completed survey forms
- Unemployment Insurance - Census, 1938 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  Completed survey forms, correspondence re the forms
- Unemployment Insurance - Census, 1938-1939 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  Forms, tables
- Unemployment Insurance - Constitutional Provisions, 1935 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  Provisions by states
- Unemployment Insurance - Costs, 1931-1933 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  Articles, charts
- Unemployment Insurance - Cost of Administration, 1936-1938 (Box 34, Folder 12)
- Unemployment Insurance - Brookwood Conference, 1932-1933 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  Opinions on unemployment insurance - quoting Chamberlain, Kellogg, and others; also a manual entitled "Outcomes for the Study of Unemployment" prepared by economics instructor, John C. Kennedy at the Brookwood Labor College; also a list of those asked to attend the Conference
- Unemployment Insurance - Federal Excise Tax, 1931-1932 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  Summary of bill providing federal aid; various booklets re unemployment insurance
- Workmen's Compensation Insurance, 1931-1942 (Box 34, Folder 27)
  Clippings, releases, notes, pamphlets, bibliography
- Unemployment Insurance - Interstate Coop, 1936-1938 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  Clippings and printed material re unemployment compensation; a report of the Interstate Conference of Unemployment Compensation Administrators
- Unemployment Insurance - Labor, 1931-1932 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  Newspaper clippings
- Unemployment Insurance - Laidler, 1930-1931 (Box 34, Folder 17)
  Laidler's articles on his view of unemployment insurance
- Unemployment Insurance - New York City, 1934-1935 (Box 34, Folder 18)
  Two page mss. by Epstein entitled, "Security in Old Age;" address delivered by Bernard "Deutsch at the YWCA headquarters, "The Relation of Unemployment Relief to Unemployment Insurance;" additional material re unemployment ins.
- Unemployment Insurance - Oppostion, 1931-1934 (Box 34, Folder 19)
  Newspaper articles, printed materials, and reports voicing opposition to unemployment insurance programs; sources include the NAM, American Academy of Political and Social Science, the VP of Metropolitan Life Insurance, etc
- Unemployment Insurance - Social Security Bill, 1933-1935 (Box 34, Folder 20)
  Pamphlets, articles, clippings
- Unemployment Insurance - Standards, 1932-1939 (Box 34, Folder 21)
  Printed material on unemployment compensation including an address on the "Six Basic Tests of Public Compulsory Unemployment Insurance," by an economist from NAM
- Unemployment Insurance - States - Clippings, 1932-1939 (Box 34, Folder 22)
  Clippings from various states re unemployment insurance; printed material including "A Comparison of State Unemployment Compensation Laws,"
- Unemployment Insurance - Wagner Bill (Box 34, Folder 23)
  10 p. mss., undated
- Unemployment Insurance - Washington, D.C., 1942-1943 (Box 34, Folder 24)
  Notes, article, clippings, leg. bills
- Veterans - Compensation, Rehabilitation, 1932-1942 (Box 34, Folder 25)
  Leg. bills, clippings, reports
- Workers Education, 1927-1937 (Box 34, Folder 26)
  Reports and printed material
- Unemployment Insurance - Duration of Benefits, 1941-1943 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  Publications, statistical material
- Ala-Ark (Box 37, Folder All)
- California (Box 38, Folder All)
- Calif-Col (Box 39, Folder All)
- Conn-Fla (Box 40, Folder All)
- Ga-Ill (Box 41, Folder All)
- Ind-Kan (Box 42, Folder All)
- Kan-Maine (Box 43, Folder All)
- Md-Mass (Box 44, Folder All)
- Massachusetts (Box 45, Folder All)
- Michigan (Box 46, Folder All)
- Minn-Miss (Box 47, Folder All)
- Mo-Mont (Box 48, Folder All)
- Neb-N.H. (Box 49, Folder All)
- N.J.-N.Dak. (Box 50, Folder All)
- New York, 1923-1939 (Box 51, Folder All)
- New York, 1940-1944 (Box 52, Folder All)
- Ohio-Ore (Box 53, Folder All)
- Pennsylvania (Box 54, Folder All)
- R.I.-S.Dak. (Box 55, Folder All)
- Tenn-Texas (Box 56, Folder All)
- Utah -Wash (Box 57, Folder All)
- W. Va. -Wyo (Box 58, Folder All)
- Wisconsin (Box 59, Folder All)
- Ariz. -Idaho (Box 60, Folder All)
- Ill - Mich (Box 61, Folder All)
- Minn - NY (Box 62, Folder All)
- NY - Ore (Box 63, Folder All)
- Penn - Tex (Box 64, Folder All)
- Utah - Wyo (Box 65, Folder All)
- Amendments to the Social Security Act (Box 66, Folder All)
- Amendments, Propaganda and Editorials (Box 67, Folder All)
- Attitude of Business Toward the SSA (Box 68, Folder All)
- Committee on Economic Security (Box 69, Folder All)
- Constitutional Problems and Cases (Box 70, Folder All)
- Editorials on Attitudes of Political Leaders (Box 71, Folder All)
- Editorial Opinion (Box 72, Folder All)
- Editorial Opinions to 1937 (Box 73, Folder All)
- Labor (Box 74, Folder All)
- Life Insurance (Box 75, Folder All)
- Payroll Propaganda (Box 76, Folder All)
- President Roosevelt (Box 77, Folder All)
- Progress of the Bill from March 1, 1953 (Box 78, Folder All)
- Reaction to Pres. Roosevelt's Proposals (Box 79, Folder All)
- Regional Offices (Box 80, Folder All)
- Reserves and Their Uses (Box 81, Folder All)
- War Displacement Bills (Box 82, Folder All)
- Australia (Box 83, Folder All)
- Austria, Belgium, Chile, Czechoslovakia (Box 84, Folder All)
- Canada (Box 85, Folder All)
- France (Box 86, Folder All)
- France, Germany, Latin America (Box 87, Folder All)
- Great Britain (Box 88, Folder All)
- Great Britain, Beveridge Plan (Box 89, Folder All)
- Italy, Irish Free State (Box 90, Folder All)
- Netherlands, Newfoundland, Norway, Poland (Box 91, Folder All)
- S. Africa, Spain, Sweden, Switzerland, Misc. (Box 92, Folder All)
- U.S., State and Local (Box 93, Folder All)
- U.S. Lundeen Bill (Box 94, Folder All)
- Business Leaders (Box 95, Folder All)
- Opinions of Individuals (Box 96, Folder All)
- Costs (Box 97, Folder All)
- Funnies (Box 98, Folder All)
- Social Security and Relief (Box 99, Folder All)
- Taxes (Box 100, Folder All)
- Social Security Act - Editorials on Supreme Court Decisions (Box 101, Folder All)
- Altmeyer, Arthur J. (Box 102, Folder All)
- Payment of Old Age Benefits (Box 103, Folder All)
- Registration of Workers (Box 104, Folder All)
- Winant, John G. (Box 105, Folder All)
- Administrative Leaders, Secretary Perkins, Political Leaders (Box 106, Folder All)
- Child Welfare and Labor (Box 107, Folder All)
- Civil Service Standards for States and Reactions (Box 108, Folder All)
- Company Welfare Plans, Dismissal Payments, Profit Sharing Plans (Box 109, Folder All)
- Health Insurance - Great Britain (Box 110, Folder All)
- Life Insurance (Box 111, Folder All)
- Life Insurance (Box 112, Folder All)
- National Resource Planning Board (Box 113, Folder All)
- Old Age Pensions, General Articles (Box 114, Folder All)
- Old Age Relief-Almshouses (Box 115, Folder All)
- Panaceas (Box 116, Folder All)
- Unemployment Insurance - Great Britain (Box 117, Folder All)
- Unemployment Insurance - New York State (Box 118, Folder All)
- Bulletin of the Association, American Association for Labor Legislation, Misc. Folder (Box 119, Folder All)
- Periodicals Containing Epstein Articles (Box 120, Folder All)
- Speeches, Articles, Scrapbooks (Box 121, Folder All)